<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<text>
	<english lang="en"><![CDATA[
	            <h2>The city that burnt down to the ground</h2>
            <img src="images/byen-som-brente.jpg" height="200" width="397" alt="Aalesund, city fire 1904" class="aligncenter"> 
            Orginal 1904 picture from <a href="http://www.bybrann.no">the city fire's own Norwegian website.</a>
            <h3>The events</h3>
            <p>The fire broke out on Aspøya, in Aalesund Preserving Co.s factory, which was where the Lower Strand Gate 39 is located today. At quarter past two in the morning, the 23 January 1904, came the first fire signal to the fire station on Lihaugen. The fire ravaged throughout the night, morning and afternoon, before it had to give up. The cause of fire was careless handling of fire.</p>
            <p>It is certainly the explanation that has become common eventually. No one will be convicted or punished for something in connection with the Ålesund Fire, but it is spoken for a while about the arson and fraud, but the rumors die away gradually. The fire stopped just west of what today is called Brusdal Hagen, ie Borgund Road 39 The last and most easterly house that burned, stood Borgund Route 37 is today.</p>

            <p>The wind was south-westerly storm with hurricane storms. Later in the day the storm passed over the more western and north western edge. Partly cloudy. Approximately 850 houses were consumed by fire, and after the fire was again about 230 houses within the city limits. Approx. 10,000 people lived in the fire area, and most of them lost their homes and most of his worldly goods.</p>
            <p>Only one died, an elderly lady who ironically lived next door to the fire station on Lihaugen. Her name was Ane Heen and was 76 years old. The people who fled were crammed together in the farmhouse and outbuildings in the areas where it had not burned, especially along Nørvøya and Borgund. Later they spread around the district.</p>
            <p>Plenty of help came to Ålesund from near and far in Norway and abroad. Much of the good help, however, was completely overshadowed by the Germany of Kaiser Wilhelm II's name, sent north. He was the one who stole the show. Ålesund's reconstruction was fully underway in the autumn 1904. And just three years later - in 1907 - were most of the burnt town was rebuilt.</p>
            <p>All text is translated orginals from the city fire website. You can use Google translate to get more.
            Go here or copy the link address to Google. <a href="http://www.bybrann.no">The Norwegian website link</a></p>
	]]>
	</english>
	<norwegian lang="no"><![CDATA[
	<h2>Byen som brant ned til grunnen</h2>
            <img src="images/byen-som-brente.jpg" height="200" width="397" alt="Ålesund, byen som brant" class="aligncenter">
            Orginalt 1904 bilde fra <a href="http://www.bybrann.no">Bybrann.no, brannens egen hjemmeside</a>
            <h3>Forløpet</h3>
	<p>Brannen brøt ut på Aspøya, i Aalesund Preserving Co.s fabrikk, som lå der Nedre 
Strandgate 39 ligger i dag. Klokka kvart over to om natta, den 23. januar 1904, 
kom det første brannsignalet inn til brannstasjonen på Lihaugen. Brannen herjet 
utover natta, formiddagen og ettermiddagen før den måtte gi seg.&nbsp; Årsaken til 
brannen var uforsiktig omgang med ild. Det er i alle fall den forklaringa som 
har blitt vanlig etter hvert. Ingen blir dømt eller straffet for noe i 
forbindelse med Ålesundsbrannen, men det snakkes en stund om ildspåsettelse og 
svindel, men ryktet dør hen etter hvert. Brannen slutta like vest for det som i 
dag kalles Brusdalshagen, det vil si Borgundvegen 39. Det siste og østligste 
huset som brente, sto der Borgundvegen 37 står i dag.</p><p>Det blåste sørvestlig 
storm med orkanbyger. Ut på dagen gikk stormen over på mer vestlig og 
nordvestlig kant. Regnbyger. Ca 850 hus ble flammenes rov, og etter brannen stod 
det igjen ca 230 hus innenfor bygrensene. Ca. 10.000 mennesker bodde i 
brannområdet, og de aller fleste av disse mistet hus og hjem og mesteparten av 
sitt jordiske gods. Kun ett menneske omkom, ei eldre dame som ironisk nok bodde 
som nærmeste nabo til byens brannstasjon på Lihaugen. Hun het Ane Heen og var 76 
år gammel. Folket som flyktet ble stuet sammen i våningshus og uthus i områda 
der det ikke hadde brent, særlig innover Nørvøya og i Borgund. Seinere blir de 
spredt omkring i distriktet.</p>
<p>Rikelig med hjelp kom til Ålesund fra fjernt og nært i Norge og i utlandet. 
Mye av den gode hjelpa ble imidlertid fullstendig overskygga av det Tyskland, i 
Keiser Wilhelm IIs navn, sendte nordover. Han var den som stjal showet.
<a href="http://bybrann.no/?page_id=32">Gjenoppbygginga</a> av Ålesund kom i 
gang for fullt ut på høsten 1904. Og allerede tre år etterpå  i 1907  var 
mesteparten av den utbrente bykjerna gjenreist</p>
	]]>
	</norwegian>
</text>
