<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<text>
	<english lang="en"><![CDATA[<h2>The company Electrocompaniet is bankrupt</h2>
    <h4> Wednesday, June 20, 2018</h4>
    The traditional Norwegian hifi manufacturer Electrocompaniet is bankrupt.<br>
    <br>
    It shows an announcement from the Brønnøysund Register.<br>
    <br>
    Electrocompany's daily chairman Mikal Dreggevik is busy meeting most of the
    day, but sends the following message to the online newspaper Tek.no via a
    colleague.<br>
    <br>
    "We can confirm that the company has declared bankruptcy, but we are working
    on a solution and hope to have it done in a short period of time.<br>
    <br>
    He currently has no opportunity to say anything about the background to
    bankruptcy.<br>
    <br>
    <h4> Deficit</h4>
    The latest available accounts for the Electrocompany are from 2016, showing
    a turnover of just over NOK 24 million and a loss after tax of 2.3 million.<br>
    <br>
    The year before, the Electrocompany sold more than 32 million, with a loss
    after tax of just over 7 million. We must return to 2013 to find a profit in
    the accounts.<br>
    <br>
    Spaceworld Soundgarden also went bankrupt recently, so there are clearly
    lean times in the Norwegian hifi industry.<br>
   <h4> On the Michael Jackson cover</h4>
    The electrocompany has a long history. The company was founded in 1973 and
    went bankrupt for the first time in 2004. They were then acquired by
    WestControl Electronics in 2007, the production moved to Tau in Rogaland.<br>
    <br>
    The company is perhaps best known for the Michael Jackson History and
    Invincible albums being produced with Electrocompaniet amplifiers, and both
    had "Special thanks to Electrocompaniet" on the cover.<br>
    <br>
    <h4> From amplifiers to multirom</h4>
    In 2011, the company expanded its portfolio with a product range called
    ECLiving, consisting of wireless multi-volume speakers with nice design and
    good sound.<br>
    <br>
    To Tek.no enlightened CEO Mikal Dreggevik before CES in January this year
    that they were ready to give more gas, was in final negotiations with
    "several of the big selling players both nationally and internationally" and
    that we in 2018 came to to hear much more from them.<br>
    <br>
    In Norway, the EC Living series has generally only been available at
    Komplett and Spaceworld Soundgarden, which is now also bankrupt. (Komplett
    is not bankrupt and lives in the best possible way). <br>
    <br>
<h2>The
soundtrack of immigrant
children shakes the United States</h2>
<h4>Tuesday 19 June 2018</h4>
<br />
<iframe
 src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PoncXfYBAVI?rel=0&amp;controls=0&amp;showinfo=0"
 allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""
 frameborder="0" height="281" width="500" /></iframe>
ProPublica has released sound recordings of several crying children who
have been taken from their parents on the border with the United States.<br />
<br />
In the seven-minute recording, ten children of immigrants from Central
America will be heard talking with border guards. The children cry and
demand their parents after being taken away from them on the border.<br />
<br />
Among the cry, a male border guard is heard:<br />
<br />
- We have an orchestra here, do not we? We only need a conductor.<br />
<br />
Two children are told not to cry.<br />
<br />
"Can I at least be with my aunt?" I want her to come, ask the girl from
El Salvador. She has pinned the phone number, and eventually gets help
calling the aunt. Another child cries uninterrupted throughout the
sound recording, and calls for his dad.<br />
<br />
2000 children in six weeks<br />
<br />
The recording puts sound on a theme that now characterizes the
political debate in the United States.<br />
<br />
Since the end of April, more than 2,000 children have been taken from
their parents and held in detention camps by the authorities after
arrival in the United States, something a child lawyer refers to as "a
form of child abuse", CBS writes.<br />
<br />
According to the news agency, AP, some of the children are kept in
cages.<br />
<br />
In May, US Justice Minister announced a new zero tolerance for illegal
immigration from Mexico:<br />
<br />
"If you smuggle a child, we will plead and that child may be separated
from you. If you do not want your children to be taken from you do not
take them over the border illegally. "<br />
<br />
France: - Certain values ​​we do not share<br />
<br />
Leading voices from both Democrats and Republicans have gone out
against the Trump administration's splitting of families, and the
president is now under strong pressure, also internationally.<br />
<br />
On Tuesday, a spokesman for the French government, Benjamin Griveaux,
stated that he did not want that what is happening now in the United
States to happen in Europe.<br />
<br />
"We do not have the same civilization model. Obviously, certain values
​​we do not share, he says to the TV channel France 2.<br />
<br />
President Donald Trump believes that the blame lies with the Democrats.<br />
<br />
<h2>Audi's chief executive has been arrested because of emissions scandal</h2>	
<h4>Monday, June 18, 2018</h4><br />
Rupert Stadler says he is innocent.<br /><br />
The German prosecutor has decided to arrest Audi chief executive Rupert
Stadler, according to AFP and Die Welt.<br />
<br />
Stadler is under investigation for Volkswagen-owned Audi's involvement
in the diesel scandal, and is now temporarily detained, confirms
Volkswagen.<br />
<br />
A week ago, the home of Stadler was investigated.<br />
<br />
<h4>Scams</h4>
<br />
The German prosecutor of the Munich Attorney General filed a trial on
30 May. Stadler and a member of the board are suspected of fraud,
according to Spiegel.<br />
<br />
Stadler has always claimed he is innocent.<br />
<br />
In January it became known that German transport authorities had found
prohibited emissions control software in several of Audi's cars, which
in turn led them to recall 127,000 cars.<br />
<br />
<h4>Volkswagen</h4>
<br />
In November, the car manufacturer had to call back 5,000 cars in Europe
to correct a software problem that caused the cars to escape too much
nitrogen oxide. It is the same gas that was the backdrop of the diesel
scandal in the owner company Volkswagen back in 2015.<br />
<br />
Volkswagen admitted by 2015 to have equipped their cars with a special
software designed to trick emission tests. It was US authorities who
discovered the software, which is located in the cars to embrace
environmental harmful emissions from diesel engines.
<br />
<br />
<h2>Expert on Trump's recall of the G7 declaration: - Not surprised</h2>
<h4>Sunday, June 10, 2018</h4>
At night Norwegian time, US President Donald Trump wrote on Twitter
that he has asked the country's representatives not to sign the final
declaration after the G7 summit. Senior scientist Hege is not surprised
and calls at the same time the president's behavior for "bullied".<br />
<br />
On Friday a highly divided G7 - consisting of Canada, France, Italy,
Japan, the United Kingdom, Germany and the United States, as well as
the EU - is gathered in Quebec. Later in the day, Canadian Prime
Minister Justin Trudeau announced that the countries had agreed on a
final declaration on all issues outside of climate. In the eight-page
end-declaration, the G7 countries promise, among other things, fighting
protectionism, preventing Iran from receiving nuclear weapons and
modernizing the World Trade Organization (WTO).<br />
<br />
After the meeting, Donald Trump twittered what could not be interpreted
as other than that he believed the meeting had been successful. - Just
went from the G7 meeting in beautiful Canada. Good meetings and
relationships with the six heads of state, he wrote.<br />
<br />
A couple of hours later the tone was different. Tonight, Trump wrote on
Twitter that he has asked the country's representatives not to sign the
final statement after the G7 summit. He also challenged Justin Trudeau
and called him too weak and cowardly.<br />
<br />
The reason for the Twitter statements was that Trudeau at a press
conference after the meeting should have promised to introduce similar
penalties imposed by the United States against Canada from 1 July. The
promise came after Trump warned the other G7 countries against such
countermeasures.<br />
<br />
Senior researcher at NUPI Hege Medin, is not surprised at the US
President's release.<br />
<br />
- Trump's last statement in which he instructs the US representatives
to withdraw support on the G7 countries agreed on is not surprising. It
is in the line of Trump's actions that contribute to weakening the
international institutions for cooperation, "Medin said.<br />
<br />
<h2>Giuliani: Trump could shoot
Comey and still not be charged</h2>
<h4>Monday 4 June</h4>
Trump attorney Rudy Giuliani heads the president's legal team and
claims the president will not pardon himself from Russia's
investigation, although he probably has the power to do so.<br />
<br />
The New York Times published a confidential letter from several of
Donald Trump's lawyers sent in January, arguing that the president does
not need to testify to specialist researcher Robert Mueller because the
position gives him the power to give himself amnesty in the
investigation and to stop the whole investigation.<br />
<br />
In the end, US law experts have discussed the content of the letter.
Former state prosecutor Preet Bharara, now legal expert for CNN, told
the channel that it would be outrageous for a seated president to give
himself amnesty.<br />
<br />
"If the president was to pardon himself, I think that would
automatically trigger a court order," he said.<br />
<br />
Trumps lawyer Rudy Giuliani has also stated on Sunday. At ABC's "This
Week," he said, "He has no intention to pardon himself" even though he
"probably has the power to do it" and at NBC's "Meet the Press" he said
it would be "unthinkable" that Trump should give himself amnesty, and
he also said that "it would probably lead the court immediately".<br />
<br />
"If he is shooting James Comey, he will be sued for the next day." They
have to put him to court first, so they can do whatever they want with
him, "said the lawyer.<br />
<br />
During the presidential campaign, Donald Trump rebuked that he could
shoot someone on Fifth Avenue "without losing votes."&nbsp;Norm
Eisen, Ethics Committee in the White House of Barack Obama, told
Huffington Post that the president's lawyers are wrong when it comes to
the president's power.<br />
<br />
<h2>Was notified of a dead person - was man who basked</h2>
<h4>Wednesday, May 30, 2018</h4>
A police officer in Stockholm received a disturbing message that
there was a dead man in a park in the Swedish capital.<br>
<br>
"My colleague was out on patrol when a man came running to him and
said there was a dead man in a park," said police inspector Viktor
Adolphson to Aftonbladet.<br>
<br>
Fortunately, when the policeman came to the spot, it did not seem to
be able to vote. The man was not dead.<br>
<br>
"There was a man who had dressed to enjoy the sun and he was fine.
He was not drunk and took it easy, says the police inspector.<br>
<br>
Asked why the suspect thought the person was dead, says the police
inspector;<br>
<br>
"It's a bit unclear. He might be pale.<br>
<br>
Furthermore, he said that it was good with committed citizens, but
that it would have been better if the tipger had taken direct
contact with the man who was asleep.<br>
<br>
	
<h2>China expresses strong
dissatisfaction with the fact that two American warships have sailed
past an island that China claims in the South China Sea.</h2>
<h4>Monday 28th of May 2018</h4>
The Chinese Department of Defense said they sent a ship to warn the two
American vessels while they were near one of the Paracel Islands. The
ministry said that the two ships sailed into Chinese waters without
requesting permission.<br />
<br />
The United States makes it clear that they sail their ships in the
South China Sea to enforce the right of free movement on the ocean and
make their opposition to the Chinese demands of the controversial sea.<br />
<br />
This posted China Daily today:<br />
<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; #PositionChina China resolutely opposes
two US warships trespassing into China's territorial waters off the
Xisha Islands, said a Ministry of National Defense spokesman.<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; - China Daily (@ChinaDailyUSA) May 28,
2018<br />
<br />
China claims 90 percent of the South China Sea, including waters
belonging to the territorial waters of the Philippines, Vietnam and
other countries around the South China Sea. The Chinese are building
bases and facilities on islands and shores that the other countries
claim.<br />
<br />
<h2>Trump declines summit with North Korea</h2>
<h4>Friday, May 26, 2018</h4>
THE WHITE HOUSE (VG) Donald Trump canceled the planned meeting with Kim
Jong-un in June. At the same time, he warns that he has "massive and
powerful" nuclear weapons. US President Donald Trump has written a
letter to North Korea's leader Kim Jong-un where he cites the summit to
be held in Singapore in June.<br />
<br />
VG is present this week in the White House together with the American
press following the president daily. In the news that Trump has
canceled the meeting with Kim, all of the TV reporters from big
channels, such as Fox News, CNN and MSNBC, jumped to reach their small
tents just outside the West Wing, where they go live on television.
Although it has been in the air that a cancellation could take place,
few of them were expecting this right now.<br />
<br />
Our nuclear weapons are massive and powerful. The letter from Trump to
Kim comes one day after North Korea called US Vice President Mike Pence
"ignorant and stupid". I looked forward to meeting you. Unfortunately,
based on the huge mind and the open-minded hostility you showed in your
recent statement, I feel it is inappropriate to conduct this
long-planned meeting at this time, Trump writes in the letter.<br />
<br />
The US president also mentions that he has more powerful nuclear
weapons than Kim. You are talking about your nuclear weapons, but ours
is so massive and powerful that I pray to God that they never need to
be used. In a press conference later in the day, Trump said he had
talked with the defense minister and the general staff after renouncing
the planned summit with North Korea's leader Kim Jong-un. Our military
is clear, if necessary, he said.<br />
<br />
However, Trump does not close the door completely and says he looks
forward to meeting the North Korean leader sometime in the future.
Meanwhile, I would like to thank you for escaping the hostages who have
now returned to their families. It was a beautiful gesture and we
really appreciate it. UN Secretary General Ant&oacute;nio Guterres
says he is deeply concerned that the meeting was canceled. North Korea
threatened itself last night to cancel the planned summit. They have
also canceled a planned meeting between Kim Jong-un and the South
Korean president, Moon Jae-in.<br />
<br />
<h2>Trump: The military is ready if necessary</h2>
<h4>Thursday, May 24, 2018</h4>
The US president says he has talked with the Defense Minister and the
General Staff after he canceled the planned summit with North Korea's
leader Kim Jong-un.<br />
<br />
"Our military is ready, if necessary, he says, adding that he has also
talked to South Korea and Japan.<br />
<br />
"They are not only ready if North Korea is doing something stupid or
flawless, but they are willing to take much of the bill for US
operations - if we are forced into something like that," said Trump.<br />
<br />
<h2>Zombie alarm in Florida</h2>
<h4>Thursday, May 24, 2018</h4>
Emergency data in Palm Beach warned of "extreme zombie activity" during
a power outage in the middle of the night.<br />
<br />
Last night to Sunday, residents experienced a nightmare in the quiet
suburbs of Lake Worth, in the county of Palm Beach on the coast of
Florida, writing the Palm Beach Post. First, thousands of residents
lost power.<br />
<br />
Then, at 01:41 at night, they could read a push message on the mobile
phone, which strikes a power outage, then hit the full zombie alarm.
However, the message tried to reassure residents that the "extreme
zombie activity" affects fewer than 7380 customers.<br />
<br />
Following the zombie alarm, the city spokesman Ben Kerr had to
complain. "I want to emphasize that at the present time, Lake Worth
does not have any zombie activity," he assured. Kerr announces that the
city "looks at the matter" about why the automatic alert system
reported zombies.<br />
<br />
The message was written in capital letters and also referred to
"Terminus". "Terminus" was one of the hangouts of Rick and his gang in
the "The Walking Dead" zombie survival scene.<br />
<br />
Kerr tells Gizmodo that the automated warning system was hacked before
August last year when a series of zombie messages were sent but were
snapped up before reaching the audience.<br />
<br />
The system has thousands of pre-programmed messages, which have been
modified to deal with zombies. The authorities are now trying to clean
the messages.<br />
<br />
Kerr says that Lake Worth investigates hacking.<br />
<br />
"Hopefully, next time there is a warning about zombie invasion, it will
be a real zombie invasion," Kerr told Gizmodo.<br />
<br />
Chaos in the emergency notification systems in the United States is
nothing new. On January 13 this year, Hawaii residents received a push
message about "incoming ballistic missile" where it was stressed that
it was not an exercise.<br />
<br />
<h2>Mother convicted in UK of forcing teen daughter to marry</h2>
<h4>Wednesday 23 may 2018</h4>
LONDON: A British jury has convicted a woman of forcing her teenage
daughter to marry a man 16 years her senior in Pakistan, a rare
criminal prosecution in England for forced marriage.<br />
<br />
The victim says she was 13-years-old, when she was forced to enter a
marriage contract with the man, became pregnant and had an abortion.<br />
<br />
She says that as her 18th birthday approached in 2016, she was tricked
into going to Pakistan for what she thought was a family vacation and
made to marry the man instead.<br />
<br />
The girl eventually returned to Britain with government help.<br />
<br />
Her mother was found guilty Tuesday at Birmingham Crown Court of forced
marriage and perjury.<br />
<br />
The woman, who can't be named to protect the identity of her daughter,
is set to be sentenced Wednesday.<br />
<br />
<h2>Islam should not have an
impact on our society - support for mosques must be stopped</h2>
<h4>Monday, May 14, 2018</h4>
As a society, we shoot ourselves in the foot if we give the same
privileges to Islam that we give to the Folk Church, "says Pernille
Vermund, leader of New Citizens.<br />
<br />
Mosques should not be treated equally with the people church. State
support for mosques must be stopped, says Pernille Vermund, leader of
the party New Citizens in Denmark.<br />
<br />
Politicians are naive in their misunderstood tolerance to Islam. The
ideology of Islam stands for all the opposite of Western values,
democracy and equality. Therefore, Islam must have no influence on our
society, "says Pernille Vermund. Vermund elaborates on a debate post
she has and another New Citizen candidate, Poul H&oslash;jlund, had
in the newspaper JyskeVestkysten Monday. (The article is not online)<br />
<br />
Here in the country one must believe and think as you please. That's
how it should be. The state must not interfere. Therefore, we must not
forbid Muslims to believe. Faith is a private matter. But Islam must
have no influence on society. Muslims' religion must remain private,
"they write in the article.<br />
<br />
&laquo;In three specific areas, the state supports Islam and
involves Islam in society. Muslims who pay to the Sharia mosques can
withdraw the amount from tax. Imams can, on behalf of the state, make
two Muslims legal formally married people. And Sharia preachers from
abroad receive a residence permit under special conditions. "<br />
<br />
"As a community, we shoot ourselves in the foot by giving the same
privileges to Islam as we give to the People's Church. Islam is both a
religion and an ideology. Islam is both faith and politics. It can not
be separated. You might think that our politicians had gradually
realized that Islam is a danger to democratic societies. Islam must not
be recognized but forced back, "writes Vermund and H&oslash;jlund.<br />
<br />
<h2>Conspiracy theories about
Hitler buried: - He did not escape to Argentina on a submarine</h2>
<h4>Saturday, May 19, 2018</h4>
Scientists have examined the dictator's teeth and skulls.<br />
<br />
For those who might have thought that Germany's dictator Adolf Hitler
did not die in 1945 but, on the other hand, fled to Argentina in a
submarine, the suspicion can now definitely be buried.<br />
<br />
We can stop all these conspiracy theories about Hitler. He did not fly
to Argentina in a submarine, he is not in a hidden base in the
Antarctica or on the dark side of the moon, says professor Philippe
Charlier, a specialist in medical and legal anthropology, to AFP news
agency.<br />
<br />
Charlier has previously also been noted with investigations of
historical individuals, both Richard Lionheart and Jeanne d'Arc.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Died
in 1945</span><br />
<br />
He and four other French scientists received access by the Russian
intelligence service FSB and Russian state archives in 2017 to
investigate a skull that was said to originate from Hitler. According
to Charlier, the skull shone well with radiographic surveys made by
Hitler's skull one year before his death.<br />
<br />
Our study shows that Hitler died in
1945, the French professor says very definitely.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Bullet
and cyanide</span><br />
<br />
The balloon hole in Hitler's skull and blue deposits on Hitler's dental
prostheses, according to Philippe Chariger's opinion, can end a
discussion as to whether the dictator died of shooting himself or
eating cyanide.<br />
<br />
"Most likely, both are", says Charlier to AFP.<br />
<br />
<h2>Royal wedding reflects a
change in Britain</h2>
<h4>Friday, May 18, 2018</h4>
When millions of people visits, or watch tv Saturday morning for the
British royal wedding, there will be talk of fairy tales and plenty of
cinematic shots of Prince Harry and his bride, Meghan Markle, riding in
a horse-drawn carriage past thousands of cheering fans with the turrets
of Windsor Castle in the background.<br />
<br />
"If you look at royal history and you look at how things are changing
in terms of diversity, the fact that Meghan Markle is going to be
married to one of the princes ... that's massive!" said an supporter.
"At the end of the day, I think it's important for me as a colored woman
to be able to identify with the leadership in this country."<br />
<br />
The family has not always been popular and their problems have gone
beyond the usual complaints about how much they cost and how much of
anachronism monarchy seems today.<br />
<br />
Royal watchers say that by accepting a self made negro woman into the
family, the Windsors will seem a little more open and a bit more in
touch with some of the shifts in the United Kingdom, particularly
multicultural London, where more than one-third of the population is
foreign-born and 41 percent are black or other minorities.<br />
<br />
But beyond the ceremony and royal craft at which the British excel,
there is a genuine story about a changing Britain, a complicated
American family, a resilient monarchy and the saving of a "difficult
prince".<br />
<br />
	
	]]>
	</english>
	<norwegian lang="no"><![CDATA[<h2>Lydopptaket
av immigrantbarna ryster USA</h2>
<h4>Tirsdag 19 juni 2018</h4>
<iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PoncXfYBAVI?rel=0&amp;controls=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
ProPublica har offentliggjort lydopptak av flere gr&aring;tende
barn som har blitt
tatt fra foreldrene sine p&aring; grensen til USA.<br />
<br />
I det syv minutter lange opptaket skal man h&oslash;re ti barn av
immigranter fra
Mellom-Amerika som snakker med grensevaktene. Barna gr&aring;ter og
ettersp&oslash;r
foreldrene sine, etter &aring; ha blitt tatt vekk fra dem
p&aring; grensen.<br />
<br />
Blant gr&aring;tingen h&oslash;res en mannlig grensevakt:<br />
<br />
&ndash; Vi har et orkester her, har vi ikke? Vi mangler bare en
dirigent. <br />
<br />
To barn f&aring;r beskjed om &aring; ikke gr&aring;te.<br />
<br />
&ndash; Kan jeg i det minste f&aring; v&aelig;re med tanten
min? Jeg vil at hun skal komme,
sp&oslash;r jenta fra El Salvador. Hun har pugget telefonnummeret,
og f&aring;r etter
hvert hjelp til &aring; ringe tanten. Et annet barn
gr&aring;ter uavbrutt gjennom hele
lydopptaket, og etterlyser pappaen sin.<br />
<br />
2000 barn p&aring; seks uker<br />
<br />
Opptaket setter lyd til et tema som n&aring; preger den politiske
debatten i USA.<br />
<br />
Siden slutten av april har over 2000 barn blitt tatt fra foreldrene
sine og
holdt i interneringsleirer av myndighetene etter ankomst i USA, noe
barneleger omtaler som &laquo;en form for
barnemishandling&raquo;, skriver CBS.<br />
<br />
If&oslash;lge nyhetsbyr&aring;et AP blir noen av barna holdt i
bur.<br />
<br />
I mai kunngjorde USAs justisminister en ny nulltoleranse for ulovlig
innvandring fra Mexico:<br />
<br />
&laquo;Smugler du inn et barn, s&aring; vil vi tiltale deg, og
det barnet kan bli
separert fra deg. Hvis du ikke vil at barna dine skal tas fra deg
s&aring; ikke ta
dem med over grensen ulovlig&raquo;.<br />
<br />
Frankrike: &ndash; Visse verdier vi ikke deler<br />
<br />
Ledende stemmer fra b&aring;de demokrater og republikanere har
g&aring;tt kraftig ut mot
Trump-administrasjonens splitting av familier, og presidenten er
n&aring; under
sterkt press, ogs&aring; internasjonalt.<br />
<br />
Tirsdag uttalte en talsmann for den franske regjeringen, Benjamin
Griveaux,
at han ikke &oslash;nsker &aring; at det som n&aring; skjer
i USA skal skje i Europa.<br />
<br />
&ndash; Vi har ikke samme sivilisasjonsmodell. Det er
&aring;penbart visse verdier vi
ikke deler, sier han til TV-kanalen France 2.<br />
<br />
<h2>Audis toppsjef er
p&aring;grepet p&aring; grunn av utslippskandalen</h2>
<h4>Mandag 18 juni 2018</h4>
Rupert Stadler sier at han er uskyldig.<br />
Den tyske p&aring;talemyndigheten har besluttet &aring;
p&aring;gripe Audi-toppsjef Rupert Stadler, if&oslash;lge AFP
og Die Welt.<br />
<br />
Stadler er under etterforskning for Volkswagen-eide Audis innblanding i
dieseljuks-skandalen, og er n&aring; midlertidig varetektsfengslet,
bekrefter Volkswagen.<br />
<br />
For en uke siden ble hjemmet til Stadler ransaket.<br />
<br />
<h4>Svindel</h4>
<br />
Den tyske p&aring;talemyndigheten ved statsadvokaten i
M&uuml;nchen tok ut siktelse 30. mai. Stadler og et medlem av
styret er mistenkt for svindel, if&oslash;lge Spiegel.<br />
<br />
Stadler har hele tiden hevdet at han er uskyldig.<br />
<br />
I januar ble det kjent at tyske transportmyndigheter hadde funnet
forbudt programvare for utslippskontroll i flere av Audis biler, noe
som igjen f&oslash;rte til at de m&aring;tte tilbakekalle
127.000 biler.<br />
<br />
<h4>Volkswagen</h4>
I november m&aring;tte bilprodusenten kalle tilbake 5.000 biler i
Europa for &aring; rette et programvareproblem som gjorde at bilene
slapp ut for mye nitrogenoksid. Det er den samme gassen som var
bakgrunnen for dieselskandalen i eierselskapet Volkswagen tilbake i
2015.<br />
<br />
Volkswagen innr&oslash;mmet i 2015 &aring; ha utrustet bilene
sine med en spesiell programvare laget for &aring; lure
utslippstester. Det var amerikanske myndigheter som oppdaget
programvaren, som er plassert i bilene for &aring; pynte
p&aring; milj&oslash;skadelige utslipp fra dieselmotorer.<br />
<br />
<h2>Ekspert om Trumps tilbakekalling av G7-erkl&aelig;ringen: &ndash; Ikke overrasket</h2>
<h4>S&oslash;ndag 10 juni 2018</h4>
I natt norsk tid skrev USAs president Donald Trump p&aring; Twitter
at han har bedt landets representanter om likevel ikke &aring;
skrive under p&aring; slutterkl&aelig;ringen etter
G7-toppm&oslash;tet. Seniorforsker Hege er ikke overrasket og
kaller samtidig presidentens oppf&oslash;rsel for
&laquo;b&oslash;llete&raquo;. <br />
<br />
Fredag samles et sterkt splittet G7 &ndash; best&aring;ende av
Canada, Frankrike, Italia, Japan, Storbritannia, Tyskland og USA, i
tillegg til EU &ndash; seg i Quebec. Senere p&aring; dagen
kunngjorde den kanadiske statsministeren Justin Trudeau at landene var
blitt enige om en slutterkl&aelig;ring p&aring; alle punkter
utenom klima. I den &aring;tte sider lange
slutterkl&aelig;ringen, lover G7-landene blant annet &aring;
bekjempe proteksjonisme, forhindre at Iran f&aring;r
atomv&aring;pen og at Verdens handelsorganisasjon (WTO) skal
moderniseres.<br />
<br />
Etter m&oslash;tet twitret Donald Trump det som ikke g&aring;r
an &aring; tolke som annet enn at han mente m&oslash;tet hadde
v&aelig;rt suksessfullt. &ndash; Dro akkurat fra
G7-m&oslash;tet i vakre Canada. Gode m&oslash;ter og forhold
med de seks statsoverhodene, skrev han.<br />
<br />
Et par timer senere var tonen annerledes. I natt skrev nemlig Trump
p&aring; Twitter at han har bedt landets representanter om likevel
ikke &aring; skrive under p&aring; slutterkl&aelig;ringen
etter G7-toppm&oslash;tet. Han langet ogs&aring; ut mot Justin
Trudeau og kalte ham for svak og feig. <br />
<br />
Bakgrunnen for Twitter-utsagnene var at Trudeau p&aring; en
pressekonferanse i etterkant av m&oslash;tet skal ha lovet
&aring; innf&oslash;re tilsvarende straffetoll som USA har
innf&oslash;rt mot Canada, fra 1. juli. L&oslash;ftet kom etter
at Trump hadde advart de andre G7-landene mot et slikt mottiltak. <br />
<br />
Seniorforsker i NUPI Hege Medin, er ikke overrasket over utspillet til
den amerikanske presidenten. <br />
<br />
&ndash; Trumps siste uttalelse der han instruerer de amerikanske
representantene om &aring; trekke tilbake st&oslash;tten
p&aring; det G7-landene kom til enighet om, er ikke overraskende.
Det f&oslash;yer seg i rekken av Trump sine handlinger som er med
&aring; bidra til &aring; svekke de internasjonale
institusjonene for samarbeid, sier Medin.<br />
<br />
<h2>Giuliani: Trump kunne skutt
Comey og likevel ikke bli tiltalt</h2>
<h4>Mandag 4 juni</h4>
Trump-advokat Rudy Giuliani leder presidentens juridiske team og hevder
presidenten ikke kommer til &aring; ben&aring;de seg selv fra
Russland-etterforskningen, selv om han trolig har makt til det.<br />
<br />
New York Times publiserte l&oslash;rdag et konfidensielt brev fra
flere av Donald Trumps advokater sendt i januar, der de argumenterer
for at presidenten ikke beh&oslash;ver &aring; vitne for
spesialetterforsker Robert Mueller fordi embetet gir ham makt til
&aring; gi seg selv amnesti i etterforskningen, og til &aring;
stoppe hele etterforskningen.<br />
<br />
I etterkant har jus-eksperter i USA diskutert innholdet i brevet.
Tidligere statsadvokat Preet Bharara, n&aring; juridisk ekspert for
CNN, sier til kanalen at det ville v&aelig;rt skandal&oslash;st
for en sittende president &aring; gi seg selv amnesti.<br />
<br />
&ndash; Om presidenten skulle ben&aring;det seg selv, tror jeg
det automatisk ville utl&oslash;se &aring; bli stilt for
riksrett, sier han.<br />
<br />
Trumps advokat Rudy Giuliani har ogs&aring; uttalt seg om saken
s&oslash;ndag. P&aring; ABCs &laquo;This Week&raquo; sa
han at &laquo;Han har ingen intensjon om &aring;
ben&aring;de seg selv&raquo; selv om han
&laquo;sannsynligvis har makten til det&raquo;&nbsp; og
p&aring; NBCs &laquo;Meet the Press&raquo; sa han at det
ville v&aelig;re &laquo;utenkelig&raquo; at Trump skulle gi
seg selv amnesti, og han sa ogs&aring; at det
&laquo;sannsynligvis ville lede riksrett umiddelbart&raquo;.<br />
<br />
&ndash; Om han skyter James Comey, vil han bli stilt for riksrett
neste dag. De m&aring; stille ham for riksrett f&oslash;rst,
s&aring; kan de gj&oslash;re hva de vil med ham, sier advokaten.<br />
<br />
I l&oslash;pet av presidentkampanjen skr&oslash;t Donald Trump
av at han kunne skutt noen p&aring; Fifth Avenue &laquo;uten
&aring; miste stemmer&raquo;. Norm Eisen, etikkavoktat i Det
hvite hus for Barack Obama, sier til Huffington Post at presidentens
advokater tar feil n&aring;r det kommer til presidentens makt. <br />
<br />
&ndash; At en president ikke kan bli tiltalt for drap? Virkelig?
Det er en av mange absurde teorier det konkluderes med ut fra deres
argumentasjon. Det er opplagt feil, sier han og legger til at en
president kan tiltales i ekstreme tilfeller - og at dette er et
ekstremt tilfelle.<br />
<br />
President Trump twitret l&oslash;rdag om brevet at det var lekket
til &laquo;Fake News Media&raquo; og gjentok at
etterforskningen er en sv&aelig;rt dyr heksejakt som er ille for
landet. Han gjentar ogs&aring; at det ikke var noen
samr&oslash;re med Russland og at de burde etterg&aring;
korrupte demokrater i stedet.<br />
<br />
<h2>Fikk melding om død person – var mann som solte seg</h2>
<h4>Onsdag 30 mai 2018 </h4>
En politimann i Stockholm fikk en urovekkende beskjed om at det lå
en død mann i en park i den svenske hovedstaden.<br>
<br>
– Min kollega var ute på patrulje, da en mann kom løpende mot han og
sa det lå en død mann i en park, forteller politiinspektør Viktor
Adolphson til Aftonbladet.<br>
<br>
Da politimannen kom til stedet viste det seg heldigvis ikke å
stemme. Mannen var ikke død.<br>
<br>
– Det var en mann som hadde kledd av seg for å nyte solen, og han
hadde det helt fint. Han var ikke beruset og tok det med ro,
forteller politiinspektøren.<br>
<br>
På spørsmål om hvorfor melderen trodde personen var død , forteller
politiinspektøren;<br>
<br>
– Det er litt uklart. Han var kanskje likblek.<br>
<br>
Videre sier han at det bra med engasjerte borgere, men at det hadde
vært bedre om tipseren hadde tatt direkte kontakt med mannen som
solte seg....<br>
<br>
<h2>Kina uttrykker sterk
misn&oslash;ye med at to amerikanske krigsskip har seilt forbi en
&oslash;y som Kina gj&oslash;r krav p&aring; i
S&oslash;r-Kinahavet.</h2>
<h2>Mandag 28.mai 2018</h2>
Det kinesiske forsvarsdepartementet sier at de sendte et skip for
&aring; advare de to amerikanske fart&oslash;yene mens de
befant seg i n&aelig;rheten av en av Paracel&oslash;yene.
Departementet sier at de to skipene seilte inn i kinesisk farvann uten
&aring; be om tillatelse.<br />
<br />
USA gj&oslash;r det klart at de seiler sine skip i
S&oslash;r-Kinahavet for &aring; h&aring;ndheve retten til
fri ferdsel p&aring; verdenshavene og gj&oslash;re klar sin
opposisjon mot de kinesiske kravene i det omstridte havet.<br />
<br />
Dette postet China Daily i dag :<br />
<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; #PositionChina China resolutely opposes
two US warships trespassing into China's territorial waters off the
Xisha Islands, said a Ministry of National Defense spokesperson.<br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &mdash; China Daily (@ChinaDailyUSA)
28. mai 2018<br />
<br />
Kina gj&oslash;r krav p&aring; 90 prosent av
S&oslash;r-Kinahavet, inkludert farvann som h&oslash;rer til
territorialfarvannene til Filippinene, Vietnam og andre land rundt
S&oslash;r-Kinahavet. Kineserne bygger baser og anlegg p&aring;
&oslash;yer og skj&aelig;r som de andre landene gj&oslash;r
krav p&aring;.<br />
<br />
<h2>Trump avlyser toppm&oslash;te med Nord-Korea</h2>
<h4>Fredag 26. mai 2018</h4>
DET HVITE HUS (VG) Donald Trump avlyser det planlagte m&oslash;tet
med Kim Jong-un i juni. Samtidig advarer han om at han har
&laquo;massive og kraftige&raquo; kjernefysiske
v&aring;pen. USAs president Donald Trump har skrevet et brev til
Nord-Koreas leder Kim Jong-un der han avlyser toppm&oslash;tet som
skulle bli avholdt i Singapore i juni.<br />
<br />
VG er denne uken tilstede i Det hvite hus sammen med den amerikanske
pressen som f&oslash;lger presidenten daglig. I det nyheten om at
Trump har avlyst m&oslash;tet med Kim la samtlige av TV-reporterne
fra storkanaler som Fox News, CNN og MSNBC p&aring; sprang for
&aring; n&aring; raskt frem til sine sm&aring; telt like
utenfor Vestfl&oslash;yen, der de g&aring;r live p&aring;
TV fra. Selv om det har ligget i luften at en avlysning kunne skje var
det f&aring; av dem som forventet dette akkurat n&aring;.<br />
<br />
V&aring;re atomv&aring;pen er massive og kraftige. Brevet fra
Trump til Kim kommer en dag etter at Nord-Korea kalte USAs
visepresident Mike Pence &laquo;ignorant og dum&raquo;. Jeg
s&aring; veldig frem til &aring; m&oslash;te deg.
Dessverre, basert p&aring; det enorme sinnet og den
&aring;penlyse fiendtligheten du viste i din nylige uttalelse,
f&oslash;ler jeg at det er upassende &aring;
gjennomf&oslash;re dette lenge planlagte m&oslash;tet
p&aring; n&aring;v&aelig;rende tidspunkt, skriver Trump i
brevet.<br />
<br />
Den amerikanske presidenten nevner ogs&aring; at han har kraftigere
atomv&aring;pen enn Kim.&nbsp;Du snakker om dine kjernefysiske
v&aring;pen, men v&aring;re er s&aring; massive og kraftige
at jeg ber til Gud om at de aldri trenger &aring; bli brukt. I en
pressekonferanse senere p&aring; dagen sa Trump at han har snakket
med forsvarsministeren og generalstaben etter &aring; ha avlyst det
planlagte toppm&oslash;tet med Nord-Koreas leder Kim
Jong-un.&nbsp;Milit&aelig;ret v&aring;rt er klart, om
n&oslash;dvendig, sa han. <br />
<br />
Trump stenger imidlertid ikke d&oslash;ren helt, og sier at han ser
frem til &aring; m&oslash;te den nordkoreanske lederen en gang
i fremtiden.&nbsp;I mellomtiden vil jeg takke deg for at du slapp
fri gislene som n&aring; er kommet hjem til familiene sine. Det var
en vakker gest og vi setter veldig pris p&aring; det. FNs
generalsekret&aelig;r, Ant&oacute;nio Guterres, sier han er
dypt bekymret over at m&oslash;tet ble avlyst. Nord-Korea truet
selv senest i natt med &aring; avlyse det planlagte
toppm&oslash;tet. De har ogs&aring; avlyst et planlagt
m&oslash;te mellom Kim Jong-un og den s&oslash;rkoreanske
presidenten Moon Jae-in.<br />
<br />
<h2>Trump: Milit&aelig;ret er klart om n&oslash;dvendig</h2>
<h4>Torsdag 24. mai 2018</h4>
USAs president sier han har snakket med
forsvarsministeren og generalstaben etter at han avlyste det planlagte
toppm&oslash;tet med Nord-Koreas leder Kim Jong-un.<br />
<br />
&ndash; Milit&aelig;ret v&aring;rt er klart, om
n&oslash;dvendig, sier han, og legger til at han ogs&aring; har
snakket med S&oslash;r-Korea og Japan.<br />
<br />
&ndash; De er ikke bare klare, dersom Nord-Korea gj&oslash;r
noe dumdristig eller skj&oslash;desl&oslash;st, men de er
villige til &aring; ta mye av regningen for operasjoner
utf&oslash;rt av USA - dersom vi tvinges til noe s&aring;nt,
sier Trump.<br />
<br />
<h2>Zombie-alarm i Florida</h2>
<h4>Torsdag 24 mai 2018</h4>
N&oslash;detatene i Palm Beach advarte om &laquo;ekstrem
zombieaktivitet&raquo; under et str&oslash;mbrudd midt
p&aring; natten.<br />
<br />
Sist natt til s&oslash;ndag opplevde innbyggere et mareritt i den
rolige forstaden Lake Worth, i fylket Palm Beach ved kysten av Florida,
skriver Palm Beach Post . F&oslash;rst mistet tusenvis av
innbyggere str&oslash;mmen.<br />
<br />
Deretter, klokken 01:41 om natten, kunne de lese en push-melding
p&aring; mobiltelefonen, som sl&aring;r fast et
str&oslash;mbrudd, for s&aring; &aring; sl&aring; full
zombie-alarm. Imidlertid pr&oslash;vde meldingen &aring;
berolige innbyggerne med at den &laquo;ekstreme
zombieaktiviteten&raquo; rammer f&aelig;rre enn 7380 kunder.<br />
<br />
I etterkant av zombie-alarmen m&aring;tte byens talsperson Ben Kerr
ut og beklage."Jeg vil understreke at p&aring; det
n&aring;v&aelig;rende tidspunkt har ikke Lake Worth noen
zombie-aktivitet", forsikret han. Kerr opplyser at byen &laquo;ser
p&aring; saken&raquo; om hvorfor det automatiske
varslingssystemet meldte om zombier.<br />
<br />
Meldingen var skrevet med blokkbokstaver og henviste ogs&aring; til
&laquo;Terminus&raquo;. &laquo;Terminus&raquo; var et
av tilholdsstedene til Rick og gjengen hans i zombie-overlevelsesserien
&laquo;The Walking Dead&raquo;.<br />
<br />
Kerr sier til Gizmodo at det automatiske varslingssystemet ble hacket
f&oslash;r august i fjor, da en rekke zombie-meldinger ble sendt,
men ble snappet opp f&oslash;r de n&aring;dde publikum.<br />
<br />
Systemet har tusenvis av pre-programmerte meldinger, som har blitt
endret til &aring; handle om zombier. Myndighetene
pr&oslash;ver n&aring; &aring; rense meldingene. Kerr sier
at Lake Worth etterforsker hackingen.<br />
<br />
Forh&aring;pentligvis, neste gang det kommer en advarsel om
zombie-invasjon, s&aring; blir det en virkelig zombie-invasjon,
sier Kerr til Gizmodo.<br />
<br />
Rot med n&oslash;dmeldingssystemene i USA er ikke noe nytt. 13.
januar i &aring;r fikk innbyggere p&aring; Hawaii push-melding
om &laquo;innkommende ballistisk missil&raquo; der det ble
understreket at det ikke var en &oslash;velse. <br />
<br />
<h2>Mor d&oslash;mt i
Storbritannia for &aring; tvinge ungdomsdatter til &aring;
gifte seg</h2>
<h4>Onsdag 23. mai 2018</h4>
LONDON: En britisk jury har d&oslash;mt en kvinne til &aring;
tvinge ungdomsdatteren til &aring; gifte seg med en mann som er 16
&aring;r gammel i Pakistan, en sjelden kriminell p&aring;tale i
England for tvangsekteskap.<br />
<br />
Offret sier at hun var 13 &aring;r gammel, da hun ble tvunget til
&aring; inng&aring; en ekteskapskontrakt med mannen, ble gravid
og hadde abort.<br />
<br />
Hun sier at da hennes 18 &aring;rsdag n&aelig;rmet seg i 2016,
ble hun lurt p&aring; &aring; g&aring; til Pakistan for det
hun trodde var en familieferie og laget for &aring; gifte seg med
mannen i stedet.<br />
<br />
Jenta kom tilbake til Storbritannia med regjeringshjelp.<br />
<br />
Hennes mor ble funnet skyldig tirsdag ved Birmingham Crown Court av
tvangsekteskap og perjury.<br />
<br />
Kvinnen, som ikke kan bli navngitt for &aring; beskytte datterenes
identitet, er satt til &aring; bli d&oslash;mt onsdag.<br />
<br />
<h2>Islam skal ikke ha innflytelse p&aring; v&aring;rt samfunn &ndash; st&oslash;tten til moskeer m&aring; stoppes</h2>
<h4>Mandag 14. mai 2018</h4>
Som samfunn skyter vi oss selv i foten hvis vi gir de samme privilegier
til islam som vi gi til Folkekirken, sier Pernille Vermund, leder for
Nye Borgerlige.<br />
<br />
Moskeer skal ikke likebehandles med folkekirken. Statens
st&oslash;tte til moskeer m&aring; stoppes, fastsl&aring;r
Pernille Vermund, leder for partiet Nye Borgerlige i Danmark.<br />
<br />
Politikerne er naive i deres misforst&aring;ede toleranse over for
islam. Ideologien islam st&aring;r for alt det modsatte af vestlige
v&aelig;rdier, demokrati og ligestilling. Derfor skal islam ingen
indflydelse have p&aring; vores samfund,&raquo; sier Pernille
Vermund. Vermund utdyper et debattinnlegg hun har og en annen Nye
Borgerlige-kandidat, Poul H&oslash;jlund, hadde i avisen
JyskeVestkysten mandag. (Artikkelen ligger ikke p&aring; nett)<br />
<br />
Her i landet m&aring; man tro og t&aelig;nke, som man vil.
S&aring;dan skal det v&aelig;re. Det skal staten ikke blande
sig. Vi skal derfor ikke forbyde muslimer at tro. Tro er en privat sag.
Men islam skal ingen indflydelse have p&aring; samfundet.
Muslimernes religion skal forblive privat&raquo;, skriver de to i
artikkelen.<br />
<br />
&laquo;P&aring; tre konkrete omr&aring;der
underst&oslash;tter staten islam og inddrager islam i
samfundslivet.&nbsp; Muslimer, der betaler til sharia-moskeerne,
kan tr&aelig;kke bel&oslash;bet fra i skat. Imamer kan
p&aring; statens vegne g&oslash;re to muslimer til lovformelige
&aelig;gtefolk. Og Sharia-pr&aelig;dikanter fra udlandet
f&aring;r opholdstilladelse p&aring; s&aelig;rlige
lempelige vilk&aring;r.&raquo;<br />
<br />
&laquo;Som samfund skyder vi os selv i foden ved at give de samme
privilegier til islam, som vi giver til Folkekirken. For islam er
b&aring;de en religion og en ideologi. Islam er b&aring;de tro
og politik. Det kan ikke skilles ad. Man skulle ellers tro, at vores
politikere efterh&aring;nden havde indset, at islam er en fare for
de demokratiske samfund. Islam skal ikke anerkendes, men
tr&aelig;nges tilbage&raquo;, skriver Vermund og
H&oslash;jlund.<br />
<br />
<h2>Konspirasjonsteorier om Hitler
gravlegges : - Han r&oslash;mte ikke til Argentina i en
ub&aring;t</h2>
<h4>L&oslash;rdag 19 mai 2018</h4>
Vitenskapsmenn har unders&oslash;kt diktatorens tenner og
hodeskalle.<br />
<br />
For dem som m&aring;tte ha trodd at Tysklands diktator Adolf Hitler
ikke d&oslash;de i 1945 men derimot flyktet til Argentina i en
ub&aring;t, kan mistanken n&aring; definitivt gravlegges.<br />
<br />
Vi kan stoppe alle disse konspirasjonsteoriene om Hitler. Han flyktet
ikke til Argentina i en ub&aring;t, han er ikke p&aring; en
gjemt base i Antarktis eller p&aring; den m&oslash;rke siden av
m&aring;nen, sier professor Philippe Charlier, spesialist
p&aring; medisinsk og legal antropologi, til nyhetsbyr&aring;et
AFP.<br />
<br />
Charlier har ogs&aring; tidligere gjort seg bemerket med
unders&oslash;kelser om historiske personer, b&aring;de Richard
L&oslash;vehjerte og Jeanne d'Arc.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">D&oslash;de
i 1945</span><br />
<br />
Han og fire andre franske vitenskapsfolk fikk i 2017 tilgang av den
russiske etterretningstjenesten FSB og russiske statsarkiver til
&aring; granske en hodeskalle som ble sagt &aring; stamme fra
Hitler. If&oslash;lge Charlier stemte hodeskallen godt overens med
radiografiske unders&oslash;kelser gjort av Hitlers skalle et
&aring;r f&oslash;r hans d&oslash;d.<br />
<br />
V&aring;r studie beviser at Hitler d&oslash;de i 1945, sier den
franske professoren meget bestemt.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Kule
og cyanid</span><br />
<br />
Kulehullet i Hitlers skalle og bl&aring; avsetninger p&aring;
Hitlers tannproteser, kan etter Philippe Charliers mening avslutte en
diskusjon om hvorvidt diktatoren d&oslash;de av &aring; ha
skutt seg selv eller av &aring; ha spist cyanid.<br />
<br />
&laquo;H&oslash;yst sannsynlig er det begge deler&raquo;,
sier Charlier til AFP.<br />
<br />
<h2>Bryllupet reflekterer en
endring i Storbritannia</h2>
<h4>Fredag ​​18. mai 2018</h4>
N&aring;r millioner av mennesker bes&oslash;ker, eller ser
p&aring; tv l&oslash;rdag morgen p&aring; det britiske
kongelige bryllupet, vil det bli snakk om eventyr og mange filmbilder
av prins Harry og hans brud Meghan Markle, som kj&oslash;rer i en
hestevogn, forbi tusenvis av glede fans med t&aring;rnene av
Windsor Castle i bakgrunnen.<br />
<br />
"Hvis du ser p&aring; kongelig historie og ser p&aring; hvordan
ting endrer seg n&aring;r det gjelder mangfold, er det faktum at
Meghan Markle skal bli gift med en av prinsene ... det er massivt!" sa
en tilhenger. "P&aring; slutten av dagen tror jeg det er viktig for
meg som en farget kvinne &aring; kunne identifisere med ledelsen i
dette landet."<br />
<br />
Familien har ikke alltid v&aelig;rt popul&aelig;r og deres
problemer har g&aring;tt utover de vanlige klagerne om hvor mye de
koster og hvor mye av anakronismens monarki som er igjen i dag.<br />
<br />
Kongelige observat&oslash;rer sier at ved &aring; akseptere en
selvstendig farget kvinne inn i familien, vil Windsorene virke litt mer
&aring;pen og litt mer i kontakt med noen av skiftene i
Storbritannia, s&aelig;rlig multikulturelle London, hvor mer enn en
tredjedel av befolkningen er utenlandsk f&oslash;dt og 41 prosent
er svarte eller andre minoriteter.<br />
<br />
Men utover seremonien og kongelige h&aring;ndverket der britene
utmerker seg, er det en ekte historie om en forandring i Storbritannia,
en komplisert amerikansk familie, et robust&nbsp; monarki og
redning av en "vanskelig prins".<br />
<br />
]]>
	</norwegian>
</text>