<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<text>
	<english lang="en"><![CDATA[<h5>Pages here will be different from the Norwegian page, because local district news isn't that interesting </h5>
<h2>National emergency preparedness campaign in Norway in the autumn</h2>
<h4>Tuesday 22 May 2018</h4>
As the Swedish authorities send out brochures to the Swedish population
where they prepare for war and crisis, DSB announces that there will be
a campaign in Norway.<br />
<br />
We are working on a separate emergency campaign that will be launched
during the autumn. Among other things, we focus on a crisis situation
where you can not access power in 72 hours. We are working on specific
advice. This will be a national campaign, and is based on much of the
same logic that the Swedish authorities write in its brochure, Cecilie
Daae, Director of Safety and Emergency Planning Directorate (DSB),
reports to ABC News.<br />
<br />
4.8 million households in Sweden will receive a brochure from Swedish
security authorities in the coming days. "If the crisis or war comes",
the title of the brochure is 20 pages long.<br />
<br />
Among other things, the authorities want to prepare the Swedes for war,
natural disasters, a major cyber attack and military conflicts.<br />
<br />
DSB will not print brochures, but will, among other things, use social
media to spread the campaign. Before Christmas last year, DSB asked the
Norwegian people how they were prepared for different types of events.
The survey showed that we have a job to do in terms of knowledge and
awareness, says the DSB boss.<br />
<br />
My comment on this is:<br />
<br />
We are now unsafe and do not have enough resources to avert a possible
threat from an eg hacker group or country. The authorities do not
provide enough money for security work and the security service is
working with old outdated machines and software. I'm sure an attack
from a relatively large group of hackers will not be stopped on time.
There are too many systems that are vulnerable and are connected to the
Internet without any particular security. So I do not feel safe in the
country I live in.<br />
<br />
<h2>We are afraid to go to the store</h2>
<h4>Tuesday 22 May 2018</h4>
Night Ravens are troubled by the development of Vestli and Stovner in
Oslo after they were attacked by several people with stones on
Saturday. It was Muslim youth who were looking for Night Ravens especially.<br />
<br />
It was the second time in three weeks.<br />
<br />
Saturday night a person was injured after someone throwing a stone at his head.
The man was transported to the emergency room with an ambulance with
cuts in his head.<br />
<br />
But it's not just the Night Ravens that are experiencing insecurity. TV
2 has talked to more people living in the area, saying they are afraid.
None of them dare to stand in front of the camera, but they say that
development has become worse.<br />
<br />
I feel that I still have to take care of me. It's so bad now that I do
not even dare to go to the store, says a lady to TV 2. Another resident
reports that she tries to avoid people who stand together. This is the
same thing that happens in some areas in Sweden, she says.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">My
comment on this is:</span><br />
<br />
Islamic truths and lack of respect come to the surface. Muslims hate us
because we are unbelievers. Then they can do anything, including
violence against us. We must stop this with laws that make Muslim
parents responsible for what their children do and then use the law to
punish them. For Muslims, it is different in terms of upbringing.
Children do not get love from their parents as Western children
receive. They also have to go to Quran schools and get brutal treatment
if they can not cite what they have learned that day. Therefore, we
must change how we treat Muslims, we must be brutal back. We are
unbelieving for them, so it does not matter what we do with them. But
they must be punished!<br />
<br />
<h2>Christian student proposes Muslim holiday</h2>
<h4>Tuesday, May 15, 2018</h4>
The leader of the Norwegian Christian Student Union, Ingvild Yrke,
proposes to "give away" some of the Christian holidays to the women's
movement, the environmental movement and Muslims.<br />
<br />
Yrke follows a recent release from the priests Einar Gelius and Per
Anders Nordengen that there are too many Christian holidays. In an
interview with the newspaper Klassekampen, the student proposes to
replace the so-called second days (second Christmas Day, Easter Day and
other Pentecost).<br />
<br />
International Women's Day March 8, World Environment Day and Id Al-Fitr
or Id Al-Adha are good alternative public holidays, says Yrke. She
shows, among other things, that the second days are a survival from the
time when many needed an extra day to get to the church. In addition,
she believes that it will be a charity act to give the Muslims a day
off.<br /><br />
<h4>My comment on this is:</h4>
I think Muslim anniversaries in Norway
should never come. We are a country of long Christian traditions. We
must continue with that, even though Christian values ​​are coming
down. We must keep the traditions and do not bow to the Muslims. Islam
is on the rise in all Western countries, so we must take care of our
own future.<br />
<br />
<h2>Norway party to seek ban on Islamic call to prayer</h2>
<h4>Sunday, april 29, 2018</h4>
Norway&rsquo;s anti-immigration Progress Party, part of
the ruling two-party coalition, is set to vote on banning the Muslim
call to prayer in Norway when it meets for its national meeting this
weekend. The proposal is aimed to counter alleged plans by some mosques
in
Norway to begin issuing the Islamic call to worship, as has been
allowed at two mosques in neighbouring Sweden. <br>
<br>
&ldquo;In several places in the country have now established
regulations under which mosques have permission to issue the call to
prayer over loudspeakers,&rdquo; claims the local party in Buskerud
county, west of Oslo, which made the proposal.&nbsp; <br>
&nbsp;<br>
&ldquo;A great many people perceive this as annoying and
inappropriate. In Norway we have freedom of religion, which should also
include the right not to be exposed to public calls to
prayer.&rdquo; The party's former leader Carl Hagen presented a
proposal for a similar
ban in 2000. <br>
<br>
But in the past, the Ministry of Justice has concluded that such a ban
would be contrary to Article 9 of the European Convention on Human
Rights, the right to freedom of thought, conscience and religion. <br>
<br>
The party&rsquo;s immigration policy spokesman, Jon Helgheim told
the V&aring;rt Land newspaper that he was not concerned with
whether the law was permissible under the Convention. <br>
<br>
&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t give a toss what human rights provisions
say in this case,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;What I care about is
that people get peace and quiet in their neighbourhoods, and that means
not being disturbed by the call to prayer. If there are conflicting
provisions in the Convention on Human Rights, I simply don&rsquo;t
care, because it's completely stupid.&rdquo; <br>
<br>
V&aring;rt Land said it had managed to find no actual examples of
mosques in Norway that are planning to begin issuing the call.<br>
<br>
<h4>My comment on this is :</h4>
Islam has no cultural tradition in Norway. A small minority tries to
get rights that the majority do not want. Call to prayers,
nikab and burka are not something we want in Norway. It is connected to
an Islamic state and we have not arrived there yet. We must see that
Norwegian traditions are maintained and minorities do not get a
"central" power and get fit into the public space. I totally condemn
Islam in public Norway.<br>
<br>
<h2>Jobseeker: 'I hope I get to slaughter all of you'</h2>
<h4>Thursday, october 1, 2015</h4>
A twenty-year-old Norwegian man sent a series of job
applications in which he praised mass killer Anders Breivik and
threatened to blow up his prospective employers.<br>
<br>
The man, who unsurprisingly was not invited for any interview, has been
charged by police and will appear in court next week. According to
Norwegian web news site ABCnyheter, the man made his first threats in
an application for a job at Akershus University Hospital.<br>
<br>
In the middle of his application, the man wrote: "Damn racists. I hope
I get to slaughter all of you soon. It's not so fucking strange that
Anders Behring Breivik became a terrorist in Norway." After failing to
get that job, he applied for a job at a local council in Oslo. <br>
<br>
"What should I do?" he wrote in the application. "Yes, I tell you what
I'll do. I'll blow you all to bits. Bomb the crap out of you all (...)
Long live Anders Behring Breivik." Again, the man was not offered a
position.<br>
<br>
He then uploaded his CV to the Norwegian Labour and Welfare
Administration's (NAV) website. The CV included the phrases "I will get
my revenge,"&nbsp; "Death to all NAV dictators", and "Long live the
Islamic State". <br>
<br>
The man's defence lawyer Bj&oslash;rn Rudjord told Norway's TV2
broadcaster that his client planned to plead guilty to making the
threats, but hoped to be able to explain that he had been feeling
frustrated at the time.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>
<br>
Background :<br>
Anders Behring Breivik killed 77 people in two separate attacks in
2011, by placing a bomb in the government quarters in Oslo and shooting
69 people at a political youth camp.<br>
<br>
<h4>My comment on this is :</h4>
We can see more of such litigation in the future. Muslims now make
their religious content public. Sharia law comes to the surface.
Norwegian values are now put to the test, and we will get the result of
the trial in Oslo's high court. It may take a while because Norwegian
courts are slow in the process of prosecution. I am against all forms
of Islamic influence in Norway. They may have their religion, but it is
private and NOT public.<br>
<br>
<h2>BEDS: 1400 in Elder Limbo</h2>
<h4>Tuesday, May 1, 2018</h4>
A new survey reveals that 1420 Norwegian elderly citizens
can't enter nursing homes due to a lack of space.<br>
<br>
The Norwegian Directorate of Health (NDH) released results of a
nation-wide, municipal survey reflecting eligible Norwegian citizens
seeking nurse-assisted living but denied care due to lack of nursing
home vacancies.<br>
<br>
&Aring;se Michaelsen, Senior &amp; Public Health Minister
released statement, saying; &ldquo;I&rsquo;m pleased that, for
the first time, we now have a national overview of people on waiting
lists for entry to nursing homes . These lists will provide elderly
care givers and their relatives predictability and security.&rsquo;
<br>
<br>
LONG-TERM PLAN<br>
&ldquo;It&rsquo;s important that we can now track the progress
of waiting list patients over time. We want full transparency about the
situation in the municipalities. Using waiting lists helps give
municipalities better overview of space requirements,and to help in
long term / short term planning,&rdquo; said Michaelsen.<br>
<br>
Per said NDH survey, April 15th saw Norway&rsquo;s townships
forward their &lsquo;waiting list&rsquo; data of qualified
patients suffering needed assistance.<br>
<br>
405 out of 422 municipalities responded to the survey; response rate of
96%<br>
&ndash; representing 98.8% of Norway&rsquo;s population.<br>
<br>
ALMOST HALF OF NORWAY<br>
The NDH report summation of municipal elderly &lsquo;waiting
list&rsquo; data reveals that almost half of Norway&rsquo;s
municipalities, 44%, see citizens awaiting admission to long-term,
assisted health care but unable to do so due to lack of space.<br>
<br>
The NDH report also reveals that of 1420 pending, long-term patients;
457 souls are currently waiting while living within their own homes.<br>
<br>
The Directorate of Health intends to review 2018&rsquo;s municipal
survey and determine if modifications or clarifications are required
before the next pending-patient survey.<br>
<br>
The Norwegian Directorate of Health is
organised under both the Ministry of Health and The Ministry of Labour.<br>
<br>
<h4>My comment on this is :</h4>
This is not good for a nation that has over $1 trillion in sovereign wealth fund.
We treat older people in an unworthy way. They do not get nutritionally
rich foods and do not have activities that give them a good life. They
helped make Norway a rich country, but in their old age they only get
the absolute minimum of services. We have a level of elderly care
comparable to developing countries and countries with high sovereign
debt. I'm not looking forward to getting old in this country.<br>
<br>
<h2>Our beautiful homeland that is not so beautiful</h2>
<h4>Monday, April 23</h4>
More than 149,900 seniors in Norway are poor. They have so low income
that they can not afford a hot meal every day. The minimum pension is
NOK 173,204. The EU's poverty line for Norway was 216,000 in 2014. At
the same time, we see that the gap between minimum pensioners and wage
recipients increases.<br />
<br />
Nearly 10 percent of people between 18 and 67 years were on disability
benefits in 2016. The new figures from Statistics Norway. A total of
331 100 people living in Norway were disabled in the National Insurance
Scheme in 2016. Of these, many are so low income that they do not have
basic services such as dentist, doctor and other things like going to a
cinema or eating at a reasonable restaurant.<br />
<br />
So there is a lot of wrong in rich Norway. Many sick people do not get
expensive medicine. The health service is inadequate and people die in
hospital corridors because there are no rooms. So we have the not so
good here in the Kingdom of Norway.<br>
<br>
<h4>My comment on this is :</h4>
With more than 1 trillion in the oil fund, it is strange that the
authorities do not show more interest to those who have the minimum
rates of economic benefits. They must be suppressed and not given any
financial freedom. You must not get sick in this country. You have to
work to live here. We sick must live at a minimum and do not have good
prospects because the government will not upgrade the benefits to a
level that is worthy.<br>
<br>	
	]]>
</english>
<norwegian lang="no"><![CDATA[<h2>Nasjonal beredskapskampanje i
Norge til h&oslash;sten</h2>
<h4>Tirsdag 22 mai 2018</h4>
Idet svenske myndigheter sender ut brosjyrer til den svenske
befolkningen hvor de forbereder p&aring; krig og krise, varsler DSB
at det kommer en kampanje i Norge.<br />
<br />
Vi jobber med en egen beredskapskampanje som skal ut i l&oslash;pet
av h&oslash;sten. Blant annet fokuserer vi p&aring; en
krisesituasjon hvor man ikke har tilgang p&aring; str&oslash;m
p&aring; 72 timer. Vi jobber med konkrete r&aring;d. Dette blir
en nasjonal kampanje, og g&aring;r ut p&aring; mye av den samme
logikken som det myndighetene i Sverige skriver i sin brosjyre,
opplyser Cecilie Daae, direkt&oslash;r for Direktoratet for
samfunns sikkerhet og beredskap (DSB), til ABC Nyheter.<br />
<br />
4,8 millioner husstander i Sverige f&aring;r i de kommende dagene
en brosjyre fra svenske sikkerhetsmyndigheter. &laquo;Om krisen
eller kriget kommer&raquo;, er tittelen p&aring; brosjyren, som
er 20 sider lang.<br />
<br />
Myndighetene &oslash;nsker blant annet &aring; forberede
svenskene p&aring; krig, naturkatastrofer, et stort cyberangrep og
milit&aelig;re konflikter.<br />
<br />
DSB kommer ikke til &aring; trykke opp brosjyrer, men skal blant
annet bruke sosiale medier til &aring; spre kampanjen.
F&oslash;r jul i fjor spurte DSB den norske befolkningen om hvordan
de var forberedt p&aring; ulike typer hendelser.
Unders&oslash;kelsen viste at vi har en jobb &aring;
gj&oslash;re n&aring;r det gjelder kunnskap og bevissthet,
forteller DSB-sjefen.<br />
<br />
Min kommentar til dette er : <br />
<br />
Vi er n&aring; utrygge og har ikke nok resurser til &aring;
avverge en mulig trussel fra en f.eks en hacker gruppe eller et land.
Myndighetene gir ikke nok penger til sikkerhetarbeid og
sikkerhetstjenesten jobber med gamle utdaterte maskiner og programvare.
Jeg er sikker p&aring; at ett angrep fra en relativt stor gruppe
hackere ikke vil bli stoppet i tide. Det er altfor mange systemer som
er s&aring;rbare og er koblet til internet uten s&aelig;rlig
sikkerhet. S&aring; jeg f&oslash;ler meg ikke trygg i landet
jeg bor i.<br />
<br />
<h2>Vi er redde for &aring;
g&aring; p&aring; butikken</h2>
<h4>Tirsdag 22 mai 2018</h4>
Natteravnene er urolige over utviklingen p&aring; Vestli og Stovner
i Oslo, etter at de l&oslash;rdag ble angrepet av flere personer
med stein. Det var muslimske ungdommer som var p&aring; jakt etter
Natteravnene.<br />
<br />
Det var andre gang p&aring; tre uker. <br />
<br />
L&oslash;rdag kveld ble en person skadet etter &aring; ha
f&aring;tt kastet en stein i hans hode. Mannen ble fraktet til
legevakten med ambulanse med kutt i hodet.<br />
<br />
Men det er ikke bare Natteravnene som opplever utrygghet. TV 2 har
snakket med flere som bor i omr&aring;det, som sier de er redde.
Ingen av dem t&oslash;r &aring; stille foran kamera, men de
forteller at utviklingen har blitt verre.<br />
<br />
Jeg f&oslash;ler at jeg stadig m&aring; se meg for. Det er
s&aring; ille n&aring; at jeg ikke en gang t&oslash;r
&aring; g&aring; p&aring; butikken, sier en dame til TV 2.
En annen beboer opplyser at hun pr&oslash;ver &aring;
unng&aring; mennesker som st&aring;r samlet. Dette er det samme
som skjer i enkelte omr&aring;der i Sverige, sier hun.<br />
<br />
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Min
kommentar til dette er :</span><br />
<br />
Islams sannheter og mangel p&aring; respekt kommer n&aring; til
overflaten. Muslimer hater oss fordi vi er vantro. Da kan de
gj&oslash;re hva som helst, inkludert vold mot oss. Vi m&aring;
stoppe dette med lovforslag som gj&oslash;r muslimske foreldre
ansvarlige for hva deres barn gj&oslash;r og s&aring; bruke
loven for &aring; straffe dem. For muslimer er annerledes
n&aring;r det gjelder oppdragelse.
Barn f&aring;r ikke kj&aelig;rlighet fra sine foreldre, som
vestlige barn f&aring;r. De m&aring; heller g&aring;
p&aring; Koran-skoler og f&aring;r brutal behandling hvis de
ikke kan sitere det de har l&aelig;rt den dagen. Derfor
m&aring; vi forandre p&aring; hvordan vi behandler muslimer, vi
m&aring; v&aelig;re brutale tilbake. Vi er vantro for dem,
s&aring; det spiller ingen rolle hva vi gj&oslash;r med dem.
Men de M&Aring; straffes!<br />
<br />
<h2>Ingrid Espelid Hovig (93) kastes ut av sykehjemmet</h2>
<h4>Fredag 18 mai</h4>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">-
Ap sparer ingen, mener Frp-politiker Aina Stenersen.</span><br>
<br>
V&aring;res alle kj&aelig;re
Ingrid Espelid Hovig (93) kastes ut av sykehjemmet der hun bor i Oslo,
fordi det privatdrevne Frognerhjemmet skal avvikles.<br>
<br>
At Hovig n&aring; m&aring; tvangsflyttes, f&aring;r flere
til &aring; reagere.<br>
<br>
&laquo;Da var turen kommet til Hele Norges matmor. Ap sparer
ingen&raquo;, skriver bystyrepolitiker Aina Stenersen (Frp) i Oslo
p&aring; Facebook.<br>
<br>
- Jeg mener Arbeiderpartiet driver en uansvarlig flytting av de eldre i
Oslo. Det er hjerteskj&aelig;rende. Her brytes gode
fagmilj&oslash;er opp, eldre sine hjem tas vekk, samtidig som
ansatte og de eldre er str&aring;lende forn&oslash;yd med
tilbudene, utdyper Stensersen overfor Nettavisen.<br>
<br>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">-
Det er hjerter&aring;tt</span><br>
<br>
Bakgrunnen for at sykehjemmet blir lagt ned, er at det ikke er toalett
og bad p&aring; alle rom, skrev Dagbladet tirsdag.<br>
<br>
Frognerhjemmet drives av stiftelsen Frogner menighets Hjem, som har
hatt en avtale med Oslo kommune som g&aring;r ut ved
nytt&aring;r.<br>
<br>
- Man kan ikke legge ned sykehjem over en lav sko bare fordi bad
mangler p&aring; rommene. Kontraktene b&oslash;r forlenges, og
anbudsreglene ses p&aring; p&aring; nytt. Det er hele 11
sykehjem og
aldershjem som Ap planlegger &aring; rasere i l&oslash;pet av
2018. Det er hjerter&aring;tt, mener Stenersen.<br>
<br>
<h4>Min kommentar til dette er :</h4>
Gamle blir til brikker i et politisk spill. Det er en sv&aelig;rt
uverdig behandlig og jeg trodde vi var kommet lengre i 2018. Eldre
m&aring; ha en forutsigbarhet og trygghet og da kan ikke
myndighetene gj&oslash;re hva de vil. Jeg gleder meg ikke til
&aring; bli gammel i Norge.<br>
<br>
<h2>Sikkerhet i h&oslash;ysetet p&aring; 17. mai</h2>
<h4>Torsdag 17 mai 2018</h4>
B&aring;de i Oslo og en rekke andre byer er det satt inn ekstra
sikkerhetstiltak i forbindelse med 17. mai-feiringen. <br>
<br>
Trass i at PST vurderer trusselrisikoen som lavere enn i fjor, er det
satt inn ekstra sikkerhetstiltak i mange byer.<br>
<br>
I hovedstaden ble ruten til barnetoget sperret av med gjerder, busser
og politibiler natt til 17. mai, og det er innf&oslash;rt generell
bev&aelig;pning av politiet.<br>
<br>
&ndash; 17. mai-opplegget er veldig likt det er i fjor. Vi har
evaluert og justert noe, trusselvurderingen er litt lavere, men
sikkerheten er p&aring; omtrent samme niv&aring;, sier
fungerende leder for felles operativ enhet i Oslo politidistrikt,
Martin Strand til VG.<br>
<br>
&ndash; Alle politifolk som er p&aring; jobb hos oss, vil
v&aelig;re bev&aelig;pnet. Det er ingen spesifikk trussel
rettet mot feiringen, men det er veldig mange mennesker ute, og det er
veldig viktig at det er trygt. Det m&aring; ligge p&aring; et
s&aring;nt niv&aring; n&aring;r s&aring; mange
mennesker er samlet, sier Strand.<br>
<br>
Trondheim og Stavanger har g&aring;tt for framskutt lagring, noe
som betyr at politiet har v&aring;pen tilgjengelig i politibilene.
I Bergen er det ikke generell bev&aelig;pning 17. mai, men politiet
vil ha punktbev&aelig;pnede patruljer p&aring; s&aelig;rlig
risikofylte steder.<br>
<br>
Ogs&aring; i en rekke andre byer ble sentrumsomr&aring;der
sperret av sikkerhetsgrunner. I Porsgrunn ble tre lastebiler
utplassert, mens fire brannbiler holdt trafikken unna Skien sentrum,
skriver Varden.<br>
<br>
<h4>Min kommentar til dette er :</h4>
Vi m&aring; ha ekstra sikkerhet p.g.a. muslimsk trussel. Vi har
importert denne trusselen med ukontrollert innvandring. Landet
v&aring;rt har ingen sikkerhet for de som har behov for det. Det er
for mange grupper med ekstreme islamske holdninger som holder seg
rolige n&aring;. De venter til de er st&oslash;rste registrerte
relegion, s&aring; kommer kravene. &nbsp;Vi har ikke
s&aring; mange generasjoner igjen f&oslash;r kravene kommer.
ABB sa 2083 i sitt forvridde og syke kompendium, jeg mener at det
kommer tidligere.<br>
<br>
<h2>Kristen studentleder
foresl&aring;r muslimsk helligdag</h2>
<h4>Tirsdag 15 mai 2018 </h4>
Leder i Norges kristelige Studentforbund, Ingvild Yrke,
foresl&aring;r &aring; &laquo;gi bort&raquo; noen av de
kristne helligdagene til kvinnebevegelsen, milj&oslash;bevegelsen
og muslimer.<br />
<br />
Yrke f&oslash;lger opp et nylig utspill fra prestene Einar Gelius
og Per Anders Nordengen om at det er for mange kristne
h&oslash;ytidsdager. I et intervju med Klassekampen
foresl&aring;r studentlederen &aring; bytte ut de
s&aring;kalte andredagene (andre juledag, andre p&aring;skedag
og andre pinsedag). <br />
<br />
Den internasjonale kvinnedagen 8. mars, verdens milj&oslash;dag og
id al-fitr eller id al-adha er gode alternative offentlige
h&oslash;ytidsdager, sier Yrke. Hun viser blant annet til at
andredagene er en etterlevning fra den tida da mange trengte en ekstra
dag p&aring; &aring; komme seg til kirken. I tillegg mener hun
at det vil v&aelig;re en nestekj&aelig;rlighet handling
&aring; gi muslimene en fridag. <br /><br />
<h4>Min kommentar til dette er :</h4>
Jeg mener at muslimske merkedager i Norge, aldri skal komme. Vi er et
land med lange kristne tradisjoner. Det skal vi fortsette med, selv om
kristne verdier er p&aring; vei nedover. Vi m&aring; holde
tradisjonene og ikke b&oslash;ye oss for muslimene. Islam er
p&aring; fremmars i alle vestlige land, s&aring; vi
m&aring; passe p&aring; v&aring;r egen fremtid.<br />
<br />
<h2>FRP vil forby b&oslash;nnerop fra moskeer</h2>
<h4>Søndag 29 april 2018</h4>
N&aring;r Frp var samlet til landsm&oslash;te i slutten av
april,
skulle de behandle et forslag om &aring; forby b&oslash;nnerop
fra moskeer i Norge. Selv om f&aring; eller ingen moskeer har det.
Partiets landsstyre har stilt seg bak forslaget fra Buskerud Frp om
&aring; forby b&oslash;nnerop fra trossamfunn i det offentlige
rom.<br>
<br>
Det heter i forslaget at det &laquo;flere steder i landet er
etablert ordninger hvor moskeer har lov til &aring; spre
b&oslash;nnerop ut over h&oslash;yttalere i byer. Dette
oppleves som sjenerende og upassende for sv&aelig;rt
mange&raquo;. Det har vakt stor oppsikt at Israel nylig har
g&aring;tt inn for
&aring; innf&oslash;r et totalforbud mot b&oslash;nnerop.<br>
<br>
Frps innvandringspolitiske talsperson, Jon Engen-Helgheim, sier han
ikke har oversikt over om det faktisk er noen moskeer i Norge som har
offentlige b&oslash;nnerop, men bedyrer at et forbud er
viktig.&nbsp;Jeg har sett at det i flere kommuner er blitt gitt
tillatelse til det. Det som er viktig i denne typen politikk,
n&aring;r det gjelder nikab, burka og b&oslash;nnerop, er
&aring; sette rammer f&oslash;r det blir et problem, sier
Engen-Helgheim, som er valgt inn p&aring; Stortinget fra Buskerud. <br>
<br>
Oslo-mosk&eacute;: Bruker app<br>
<br>
Styrelederen ved Oslo-moskeen Islamic Cultural Center sier dette
h&oslash;res ut som en problemstilling som er 15 &aring;r
gammel.&nbsp;N&aring;r det kommer til b&oslash;nnerop,
bruker vi app i 2018. Vi bruker ikke b&oslash;nnerop for
&aring; tilkalle folk. B&oslash;nneropets funksjon var jo
&aring; 10 minutter f&oslash;r b&oslash;nnen minne folk
p&aring; at de m&aring;tte gj&oslash;re seg klare, sier
styreleder Arshad M. Jamil. <br>
<br>
<h4>Min kommentar til dette er :</h4>
Islam har ingen kulturell tradisjon i Norge. En liten minoritet
fors&oslash;ker &aring; f&aring; rettigheter som
majoriteten ikke vil ha. B&oslash;nnerop,&nbsp;nikab og burka
er ikke noe vi vil ha i Norge. Det er forbundet til en islamsk stat og
vi er ikke kommet dit enn&aring;. Vi m&aring; se at norske
tradisjoner holdes i hevd og at minoriteter ikke f&aring;r en
"sentral" makt og f&aring;r innpass i det offentlige rom. Jeg er
helt imot at Islam f&aring;r noen rolle i det offentlige Norge.<br>
<br>
<h2>V&aring;rt vakre fedreland
som ikke er s&aring; vakkert</h2>
<h4>Onsdag 11 april 2018</h4>
Flere enn 149.900 eldre i Norge er fattige. De har s&aring; lav
inntekt at de ikke har r&aring;d til et varmt m&aring;ltid hver
dag. Minste&shy;pensjonen er p&aring; 173.204 kroner. EUs
fattigdomsgrense for Norge var i 2014 p&aring; 216.000 kroner.
Samtidig ser vi at avstanden mellom minstepensjonister og
l&oslash;nnsmottakere &oslash;ker.<br />
<br />
Nesten 10 prosent av folk mellom 18 og 67 &aring;r var p&aring;
uf&oslash;retrygd i 2016. Det viser nye tall fra SSB. I alt 331 100
personer bosatt i Norge var uf&oslash;retrygdede i folketrygden i
2016. Av disse er det mange med s&aring; lav inntekt at de ikke har
mulighet til basiske tjenester som tannlege, lege og andre ting som
f.eks.&aring; g&aring; p&aring; kino eller spise
p&aring; en rimlig restaurant. <br />
<br />
S&aring; det er mye galt i rike Norge. Mange syke mennesker
f&aring;r ikke dyr medisin. Helsetjenesten er mangelfull og folk
d&oslash;r i sykehuskorridorer fordi det ikke finnes rom.
S&aring; vi har det ikke s&aring; bra her i kongeriket Norge.<br>
<br>
<h4>Min kommentar til dette er :</h4>
Med mer enn 1 trillion i oljefondet, er det merkelig at myndighetene
ikke viser mer interesse for de som har minstesatser
&oslash;konomiske ytelser. De skal undertrykkes og ikke gis litt
&oslash;konomsk frihet. Du m&aring; ikke bli syk i dette
landet. Du m&aring; jobbe for &aring; leve her. Vi syke
m&aring; leve p&aring; minimum og har ikke gode
fremtidsutsikter fordi regjeringen vil ikke oppjustere ytelsene til et
niv&aring; som er verdig.<br>
<br>
]]>
	</norwegian>
</text>